A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Audiovisual materials FA750
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Videotapes, 80 Item(s) 80 videotapes of various formats including 2" Quad, 3/4" Umatic, VHS and Digital Betacam.; Except where noted, the Ford Foundation videotapes are only available in their original format.
  - Open Mind, 17 March 1982; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10037)
    Host Richard Heffner interviewing Frank Thomas.
  - Operation Goodwill: Homeless, VHS (Tape AV 10567)
  - Our Common Road, 1985; VHS (Tape AV 10566)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08550526 (PA855-526), The Union of American Hebrew Congregations, SUPPORT OF CONFERENCE ACTIVITIES ON BLACK-JEWISH RELATIONS.
    Representative Charles Rangle and Representative Steve Solarz
  - Pat Ewing, VHS (Tape AV 10565)
  - People Who Have Struggled With Abortion, VHS (Tape AV 10564)
  - The Patterson Project: One City in the Reagan Era, 21 November 1984; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10039)
    Producer H. Husock
  - Perspectives, 9 June 1980; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10040)
  - Perspectives, 9 June 1980; 3/4" Umatics (Tape AV 10041)
  - Prime Time - Return of the Prodigy, 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10042)
  - Q & A's with Franklin Thomas, 22 April 1982; VHS; 27:45 minutes. (Tape AV 10587)
  - Q & A's with Franklin Thomas, 22 April 1982; VHS; 27:45 minutes. (Tape AV 10585)
  - Q & A's with Franklin Thomas, 22 April 1982; VHS; 27:45 minutes. (Tape AV 10588)
  - Q & A's with Franklin Thomas, 22 April 1982; VHS; 27:45 minutes (Tape AV 10586)
  - Q & A's with Franklin Thomas, 3/4" Umatic; 30 minutes. (Tape AV 10043)
    with Charlene Hunte Gault. Abridged version. Also, WPIX interview.
  - Red, White & Blue Productions: NASS/ACEP 1984 Vote Campaign, 5 October 1984; VHS (Tape AV 10569)
    19 spots.
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08450558 (PA84-558), American Citizenship Education Project, SUPPORT OF NATIONAL MEDIA PROJECT TO ENCOURAGE VOTER REGISTRATION AND PARTICIPATION.
  - Sex, Drugs & AIDS, April 1987; VHS (Tape AV 10044)
    Separated from Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Office of the Program Director, Papers of Shepard Forman (2012:074:002).
  - Straight Talk, 24 November 1981 (Tape AV 10045)
    Segment on Leadership with Edward J. Meade, Jr. in discussion of Ford Foundation's Leadership Development Program
  - The Subject is: AIDS, 1987; 18 minutes.; VHS (Tape AV 10046)
    Separated from Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Office of the Program Director, Papers of Shepard Forman (2012:074:003).
  - The Sukhomajri Experience, VHS (Tape AV 10578)
  - Ted Bryant Show, 23 November 1985; VHS (Tape AV 10576)
    KOIN-TV - Portland
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 20 September 1991; VHS; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10577)
    Videotape version of "That Our Children Will Not Die" 6 April 1981.
  - Transformation Through Media, 1992; VHS; 20 minutes. (Tape AV 10571)
  - Turning Around, VHS (Tape AV 10572)
  - Turning Around, VHS (Tape AV 10583)
  - The Urban Project, 4 February 1983; Betacam (Tape AV 10584)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08100908 (PA81-908), Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY), PARTIAL SUPPORT OF PLANNING FOR URBAN PROJECT: MINORITY STUDENTS ADVANCEMENT IN SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGIES.
  - The Walls Come Tumbling Down, 6 February 1997; VHS (Tape AV 10581)
    Film transferred to video on 6 February 1997.
  - The Walls Come Tumbling Down, VHS (Tape AV 10582)
  - What Happened in Seattle?: The Origins of a School Desegregation Plan, September 1980; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10048)
  - Women's Project Directing Program: 1983-1984 Season, VHS (Tape AV 10580)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08400057 (PA84-57), The American Place Theatre, Inc., SUPPORT FOR WOMEN'S PROJECT TRAINING PROGRAM FOR STAGE DIRECTORS.
  - Women Who Didn't Have an Abortion; Women Who Have Had an Abortion, 1983; 57 minutes. (Tape AV 10049)
    See also Ford Foundation grant, 08300825 (PA83-825), Martha Stuart Communications, Inc., PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR PRODUCTION AND DISTRIBUTION OF A VIDEOTAPE ON PEOPLE WHO HAVE STRUGGLED WITH THE ABORTION DECISION (RHG).
  - Yale University: Phil Garvin, 26 December 1978; 3/4" Umatic; 30 minutes. (Tape AV 10050)
    Kodaly Film. Final Edit.
- Ford Foundation Audio
  Access Restrictions
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply.
  - Black Women's Unity Drive, National Council of Negro Women, Inc., 1973 (Box 4, Reel AV 8702)
  - McGeorge Bundy interview, WCCO Radio, Boone-Erickson Show, 1972 November 9 (Box 1, Reel AV 8652)
  - McGeorge Bundy interview, KSTP-TV, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1972 November 19 (Box 1, Reel AV 8655)
  - McGeorge Bundy speech at Foundation Luncheon Group meeting, New York City, 1973 March 22 (Box 1, Reel AV 8659)
    For Visual Scope by Tom McGuire.
  - Calcutta, India Planning, Snag Club meeting, 1963 December 11 (Box 1, Reel AV 8660)
    Echeverria, Wood and Whittlesey speaking.
    Urban policy; City planning
  - Foundations in Focus, WNBC-RM, Richard Magat interview, 1963 March 11 (Box 1, Reel AV 8657)
    Thomas P. Robins- host, Richard Magat. Prepared for Harold A. Klein at the Elsberg Studio.
  - Eoan Group Opera (Box 1, Reel AV 8656)
    Recording of excerpts from various presentations of Italian opera by the Non-White Eoan Group of Cape Town, South Africa.
  - Paul Hoffman interview, 1953 January 25 (Box 4, Reel AV 8696)
    "U.S. Department of State, Property of U.S. Government."
  - Dr. Laurence Gould speech to Ford Foundation staff, 1955 October 3 (Box 4, Reel AV 8701)
    "Dr. Laurence Gould will speak to the Foundation staff on Monday October 3. He will talk on past polar expeditions, including those in which he participated, and similar expeditions planned in connection with the International Geophysical Year, 1957-58."
  - Gaon Sathis, 1954 April 12 (Box 4, Reel AV 8697)
    Composite Safety, Kleinberg, New American Version.
  - International agriculture press conference, Rockefeller Foundation and Ford Foundation, 1968 April 4 (Box 1, Reel AV 8661)
  - IUD (Intrauterine Device): The New Contraceptive, 1965 (Box 1, Reel AV 8653)
    Contraceptives; Family planning
  - Negro Student Fund meeting held at Saint Albans School, 1966 January 19 (Box 1, Reel AV 8658)
    Remarks by Louis Martin, David Mallery, and Hon. Nicholas Katzenbach.
    See also Ford Foundation grant 06400422 (PA64-422), The National Association Of Housing And Redevelopment Officials, SEMINARS TO IMPROVE THE DESIGN OF PUBLIC HOUSING.
  - Night Call, demonstration tape (Box 1, Reel AV 8662)
    2012.082.001
  - Night Call, equipment test tape sampling (Box 1, Reel AV 8663)
    2012.082.002
  - Tape Selections for Manual, 1972 (Box 3, Reel AV 8695)
    Accompanying material for "Students Manual for Teaching Standard English Writing to Speakers Showing Black English Influences in their Writing", Language Curriculum Research Group. See also Ford Foundation grant (PA70-444), Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY), PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR AN ENGLISH-LANGUAGE DEMONSTRATION PROJECT-- THE LANGUAGE CURRICULUM RESEARCH GROUP.
  - Verbatim remarks by McGeorge Bundy, National Association of Educational Broadcasters, 1968 November 20 (Box 1, Reel AV 8654)
  - [Unlabeled], 1968 April 4 (Box 1, Reel AV 8664)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8668)
    Mathematical Discourses for African Teacher Training Colleges. Recorded at Education Development Center, Newton, Massachusetts. Funded under Ford Foundation grant 06600101 (PA66-101), Education Development Center, Inc., TEACHER TRAINING INSTITUTES FOR THE IMPROVEMENT OF MATHEMATICS TEACHING IN AFRICA.
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8669)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8670)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8671)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8672)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8673)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8674)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8675)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8676)
  - Entebbe Mathematics Series, African Mathematics Program, 1970 (Box 2, Reel AV 8677)
  - Cross-Cultural Learner Centre, London, Ontario, Canada, - Media/Government, Case I, Professor Messon (Box 3, Reel AV 8678)
    File Plan
    MP 120
  - Cross-Cultural Learner Centre, London, Ontario, Canada, - Media/Government, Case II and III, Professor Miller (Box 3, Reel AV 8679)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Pacoima - tutor discussion session (Box 2, Reel AV 8680)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Pacoima - tutoring, 1973 April 26 (Box 2, Reel AV 8681)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Teachers' meeting, 1973 April 26 (Box 2, Reel AV 8682)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Evening at home of parent, 1973 April 26 (Box 2, Reel AV 8683)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Evening - ladies at coffee table, 1973 April 26 (Box 2, Reel AV 8684)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Wilshire Crest - auditorium, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8685)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Wilshire Crest - tutor teaching, how to pay game, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8686)
  - Tutorial Community Project - YO interview - wild - tutor training, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8687)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Wilshire Crest - tutor training - library, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8688)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Tutorial Community Project - Quest, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8689)
  - Tutorial Community Project - Tutorial Community Project - Quest, 1973 April 27 (Box 2, Reel AV 8690)
  - Conference - Sterling Forest, New York, 1969 December 1-3 (Box 2, Reel AV 8691)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 06890743 (PA68-743), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PLANNING AND PRELIMINARY DEVELOPMENT OF A PROGRAM TO DEVELOP NEW PATTERNS OF EDUCATION FOR SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS.
  - Conference - Sterling Forest, New York, 1969 December 1-3 (Box 2, Reel AV 8692)
  - Conference - Sterling Forest, New York, 1969 December 1-3 (Box 3, Reel AV 8693)
  - Conference - Sterling Forest, New York, 1969 December 1-3 (Box 3, Reel AV 8694)
  - The People Act in the San Joaquin Valley of California, 1952 May 4, 10:05-10:30 PM, EST (Box 4, Reel AV 8698)
    Alternate item ID
    XTV17201
    CBS Radio Network
  - The People Act in Alexandria, Minnesota, 1952 June 8, 10:05-10:30 PM, EST (Box 4, Reel AV 8699)
    XTV17206
  - The People Act in Essex County, New Jersey, 1952 April 27, 10:05-10:30 PM, EST (Box 4, Reel AV 8700)
    XTV17200